TABITHA TOWNES

(707) 592-6297 Tabithatownes@gmail.com

1300 Burton Dr, APT 291 Vacaville, CA 95687



https://www.linkedin.com/in/tabitha-townes-77a64248/



https:// tmtownes.github.io/ Portfolio-Website/

PROFILE

As a career-changer, I am dedicated to bringing the wealth of my creative background to becoming a Java Full Stack Developer. My unique personal and professional experience, both domestic and abroad, contributes to my goal-oriented approach to programming and project development. Contributing to my success, is my tenacious curiosity and lifelong learner attitude.

SKILLS

- ReactJs
- JavaScript
- PostrgesSQL
- Node.Js
- R Studios
- Python
- Microsoft Office Suites

- Business Intelligence
- Complex Problem Solving
- Presentation Development
- Professional Communication
- Procedural Compliance
- · Interpersonal Interviewing
- · Intermediate Spanish

EXPERIENCE

Associate Developer, Revature; Remote — Jun 2022-Oct 2022

Built a complete Java web API using MVC and Front Controller design patterns. Generated PostgresSQL AWS RDS with DBeaver interface. Created dynamic React web applications with mobile flexibility and map functions. Organized Agile Scrum, DevOps services, and REST frameworks.

Human Services Specialist, County of San Diego, CA — Jan 2020-Jun 2022

Conducted client interviews to obtain and verify PINs for public assistance services. Analyzed government applications to determine eligibility.

Managed caseloads and generated reports for ongoing cases.

UI/UX Designer, Imagine The Stage (ITS); Remote — Sep 2019-Jun 2020

Designed frontend web frameworks and communicated with stakeholders to implement product visual and functional requirements. Verified program logic using testing and debugging best practices.

Robotics Educator, Sacred Heart School; Barcelona, Spain — 2016-2019

Developed educational STEM program for coding and elementary physics. Monitored key performance indicators for multiple student classes. Instructed in basic robot design, programming, and testing.

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis — International Relations, B.A. 2012